A Guide to the John D. Rockefeller 3rd papers FA108
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller Files, 1906-1969 1906-1961; 1; 34.5 Cubic Feet 98 Boxes
  - Personal Papers, 1906-1961; 1
    - Pocantico Hills - Estate Services, 1939-1946 (Box 16, Folder 140)
    - Pocantico Hills - Furnishings, 1933, 1940, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 141)
    - Pocantico Hills - Sheep Raising, 1942-1943 (Box 16, Folder 142)
    - Pocantico Hills - Taxes, 1941-1945 (Box 16, Folder 143)
    - Pocantico Hills - Water Supply and Fire Protection, 1939-1943 (Box 16, Folder 144)
    - Pocantico Hills - Water Supply and Fire Protection, 1939-1943 (Box 16, Folder 145)
    - Publicity, 1929, 1952-1959 (Box 16, Folder 146)
    - Red Cross Service, 1941-1951 (Box 16, Folder 147)
    - Religion, Drinking, and Philosophy Notes, 1931, 1942, 1950, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 148)
    - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich - Condolences (A-G), 1948 (Box 16, Folder 149)
    - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich - Condolences (H-Z), 1948 (Box 17, Folder 150)
    - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich - Condolences (H-Z), 1948 (Box 17, Folder 151)
    - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich - Memorials, 1948-1956 (Box 17, Folder 152)
    - Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker, 1933-1961 (Box 17, Folder 153)
    - Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker, 1933-1961 (Box 17, Folder 154)
    - Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker - Gifts for, 1932-1959, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 155)
    - Rockefeller, Blanchette Hooker - Musicale (February 1936), 1935-1936 (Box 17, Folder 156)
    - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1948-1954, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 157)
    - Rockefeller, John D., Sr. - Condolences, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 158)
    - Rockefeller, John D., Jr. - Biography, 1944-1957 (Box 17, Folder 159)
    - Rockefeller, John D., Jr. - Gifts from, 1927-1950 (Box 17, Folder 160)
    - Salary, 1930-1938 (Box 17, Folder 161)
    - Schools - Notebook, 1915-1919 (Box 18, Folder A)
    - Schools - Notebook, 1915-1919 (Box 18, Folder B)
    - Schools - Notebook, 1915-1919 (Box 18, Folder C)
    - Schools - Notebook, 1915-1919 (Box 18, Folder D)
    - Schools - Notebook, 1915-1919 (Box 19, Folder E)
    - Schools - Notebook, 1915-1919 (Box 19, Folder F)
    - Schools - Notebook, 1915-1919 (Box 19, Folder G)
    - Schools - Notebook, 1915-1919 (Box 19, Folder H)
    - Schools - Notebook, 1915-1919 (Box 19, Folder I)
    - Schools - Loomis Institute, 1921-1929, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 162)
    - Schools - Loomis Institute - Yearbook, 1925 (Box 20, Folder 163)
    - Schools - Princeton University, 1924-1930 (Box 20, Folder 164)
      - Princeton graduation (Box P 170, Folder 2)
        photographic material separated from the body of the collection.
    - Schools - Princeton University - "Daily Princetonian", 1925-1927 (Box 20, Folder 165)
    - Schools - Princeton University - "Freshman Herald", 1925 (Box 20, Folder 166)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Thesis ("Industrial Relations Plans"), 1929 (Box 20, Folder 167)
    - Schools - Loomis School - The Loomis Handbook, 1921-1925 (Box 20A, Folder 1)
    - Schools - Loomis School - The Loomis Institute, 1921-1925 (Box 20A, Folder 2)
    - Schools - Loomis School - The Loomis School Lesson Book, 1923-1924 (Box 20A, Folder 3)
    - Schools - Loomis School - Physics Laboratory, 1923-1924 (Box 20A, Folder 4)
    - Schools - Loomis School - United States History A, 1921-1925 (Box 20A, Folder 5)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Architecture 202, 1925-1929 (Box 20A, Folder 6)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Art 201, 1925-1929 (Box 20A, Folder 7)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Art 303 - Italian Painting, 1925-1929 (Box 20A, Folder 8)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Art 404 - Modern Painting, 1925-1929 (Box 20A, Folder 9)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Chemistry 101, 1925-1929 (Box 20A, Folder 10)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Chemistry 102 - Laboratory Notebook, 1925-1929 (Box 20A, Folder 11)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Economics, 1925-1929 (Box 20A, Folder 12)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Economics 303 - Labor Problems, 1925-1929 (Box 20A, Folder 13)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Economics 304 - Public Finance, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 14)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Economics 401 and Politics 303, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 15)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Economics 402 - International Finance, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 16)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Economics 406 - Social Reorganization, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 17)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Economics 407 - Government and Business, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 18)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Economics 408 - Transportation, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 19)
    - Schools - Princeton University - English 201-202 - Public Speaking, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 20)
    - Schools - Princeton University - French 201-202, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 21)
    - Schools - Princeton University - General Knowledge, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 22)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Geology 201-202 - Lecture Notes, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 23)
    - Schools - Princeton University - "Geology Manual No. 2: An Introduction and Laboratory Manual in Elementary Historical Geology", 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 24)
    - Schools - Princeton University - History - Modern European History, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 25)
    - Schools - Princeton University - An Introduction to History Politics and Economics - Outline of "Anthropology", 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 26)
    - Schools - Princeton University - An Introduction to History Politics and Economics - Outline of "Principles of Human Geography", 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 27)
    - Schools - Princeton University - An Introduction to History Politics and Economics - Outlines, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 28)
      Outlines of "Social Science" and "Man and Culture"
    - Schools - Princeton University - History 201 - Europe, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 29)
    - Schools - Princeton University - History 201-202 - Lecture Notes, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 30)
    - Schools - Princeton University - History 202 - Outlines, 1925-1929 (Box 20B, Folder 31)
      Outlines of "Political and Social History of Europe" and "History of Modern Europe"
    - Schools - Princeton University - Princeton Commencement, 1929 (Box 20C, Folder 32)
    - Expenses - Personal Expense Ledger, 1919-1921 (Box 20C, Folder 33)
    - Expenses - Clothes Account, January 1922 (Box 20C, Folder 34)
    - Expenses, 1922-1924 (Box 20C, Folder 35)
    - Expenses - Personal Expense Ledger, 1925-1927 (Box 20C, Folder 36)
    - Expenses - Travel Expense Ledger - Europe, April 1926 (Box 20C, Folder 37)
    - Expenses - Travel Expense Ledger - Europe, 1927-1928 (Box 20C, Folder 38)
    - Expenses - Expense Account, 1927 (Box 20C, Folder 39)
    - Expenses - Expense Account, January 1928-June 1929 (Box 20C, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence - Blanchette Hooker Rockefeller, 1943-1947 (Box 20C, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence - John D. Rockefeller 3rd, 1929-1948 (Box 20C, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence - List of Books and Their Authors, Alphabetically Arranged, 1914-1918 (Box 20C, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence - Response Cards for April 20, 1918 Party (Box 20C, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence - World Tour - Orient - Letters Written by J. MacDonald, 1929 (Box 20C, Folder 45)
    - Schools - Princeton University - Diplomas and Scrapbook, 1925-1929 (Box 21, Folder 167A)
    - Scrapbook (News Clippings), 1937-1941 (Box 21, Folder 167B)
    - Summers, 1939-1942, 1946-1957 (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Summer, 1939 (Box P 170, Folder 3)
    - Summers, 1939-1942, 1946-1957 (Box 22, Folder 169)
    - War Bonds, 1945, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 170)
    - Wedding, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 171)
    - Wedding - Expenses, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 172)
    - Wedding - Gifts, 1932-1933 (Box 22, Folder 173)
    - Wedding - Invitation List, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 174)
    - Wedding - Marriage Certificate, 1932 (Box 22, Folder 175)
    - Washington, D.C. House, 1942-1950 (Box 22, Folder 176)
    - Fieldwood Farm and John D. Rockefeller, the 3rd residence plans, File includes 20 drawings (Box Cabinet B Drawer 2, Folder 93)
    - Fieldwood Farm plans, Quantity: 24 (Box Cabinet B Drawer 2, Folder 92)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1906-1966 1906-1961; 2
    Divided into chronological and alphabetical segments.
    The vast majority of the correspondence is incoming with a few carbon copies of Rockefeller's outgoing letters. This subseries includes the letters to Rockefeller from his mother, wife, siblings, and other extended family (Rockefeller and Hooker) members. Of special note is the correspondence between Rockefeller and his father (folders 287-300), which reveals much about their relationship, most especially JDR 3rd's drive to please his father. Other correspondents include Rockefeller's girlfriends and female acquaintances (such as Anne Colby, Alida Milliken, Elizabeth "Pete" Peterson, and Betty Stickney) and school chums, some of whom became lifelong friends (William Cochran, Douglas Dillon, Douglas Robertson, Bob Russell, and Latimer Stewart, among others). Also included in this subseries are letters to Rockefeller from his former nurse-governess, Florence Scales, and from Fannie Evans, John D. Rockefeller Sr.'s housekeeper, as well as from Benjamin and David Rowntree, the British children to whom Rockefeller and his wife were foster parents during the World War II. The "Famous People" file (folder 237) includes correspondence from Jane Addams, Dean Acheson, Winston Churchill, Indira Gandhi, Jacqueline Kennedy, U Thant, and Shigeru Yoshida, among others.
    - Correspondence - Unarranged, undated (Box 23, Folder 177)
    - Correspondence - Unarranged, undated (Box 23, Folder 178)
    - Correspondence - Unarranged, undated (Box 23, Folder 179)
    - Correspondence - Unarranged, undated (Box 23, Folder 180)
    - Chronological, 1916-1931 (Box 23, Folder 181)
    - Chronological, 1916-1931 (Box 23, Folder 182)
    - Chronological, 1916-1931 (Box 23, Folder 183)
    - Chronological, 1916-1931 (Box 23, Folder 184)
    - Chronological, 1916-1931 (Box 23, Folder 185)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 186)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 187)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 188)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 189)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 190)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 191)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 192)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 193)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 194)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 195)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 196)
    - Chronological, 1931-1942 (Box 24, Folder 197)
    - Chronological, 1943-1952 (Box 25, Folder 198)
    - Chronological, 1943-1952 (Box 25, Folder 199)
    - Chronological, 1943-1952 (Box 25, Folder 200)
    - Chronological, 1943-1952 (Box 25, Folder 201)
    - Chronological, 1943-1952 (Box 25, Folder 202)
    - Chronological, 1943-1952 (Box 25, Folder 203)
    - Chronological, 1943-1952 (Box 25, Folder 204)
    - Chronological, 1943-1952 (Box 25, Folder 205)
    - Chronological, 1943-1952 (Box 25, Folder 206)
    - Chronological, 1943-1952 (Box 25, Folder 207)
    - Chronological, 1953-1961 (Box 26, Folder 208)
    - Chronological, 1953-1961 (Box 26, Folder 209)
    - Chronological, 1953-1961 (Box 26, Folder 210)
    - Chronological, 1953-1961 (Box 26, Folder 211)
    - Chronological, 1953-1961 (Box 26, Folder 212)
    - Chronological, 1953-1961 (Box 26, Folder 213)
    - Chronological, 1953-1961 (Box 26, Folder 214)
    - Chronological, 1953-1961 (Box 26, Folder 215)
    - Chronological, 1953-1961 (Box 26, Folder 216)
    - Chronological, 1953-1961 (Box 26, Folder 217)
    - Alphabetical (A-Z), 1927-1931 (Box 27, Folder 218)
    - Alphabetical - Albertson, Alta, 1920-1926 (Box 27, Folder 219)
    - Alphabetical - Aldrich, Lucy T., n.d. (Box 27, Folder 220)
    - Alphabetical - Aldrich, Winthrop, 1953-1956 (Box 27, Folder 221)
    - Alphabetical - Bilkey, H. E., 1939-1953 (Box 27, Folder 222)
    - Alphabetical - Blake, Benson, 1926-1929, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 223)
    - Alphabetical - Bok, William Curtis, 1928 (Box 27, Folder 224)
    - Alphabetical - Bowles, Chester, 1954-1959 (Box 27, Folder 225)
    - Alphabetical - Bridgetts, Jeanne E., 1943-1946 (Box 27, Folder 226)
    - Alphabetical - Cobb, Philip, 1922-1928 (Box 27, Folder 227)
    - Alphabetical - Cochran, William F., 1927-1930 (Box 27, Folder 228)
    - Alphabetical - Colby, Anne, 1923-1927 (Box 27, Folder 229)
    - Alphabetical - Dillon, C. Douglas, 1958-1964 (Box 27, Folder 230)
    - Alphabetical - Dodge, Marcellus H., Jr., 1925-1926 (Box 27, Folder 231)
    - Alphabetical - Dulles, Allen W., 1959 (Box 27, Folder 232)
    - Alphabetical - Dulles, John Foster, 1952-1959 (Box 27, Folder 233)
    - Alphabetical - Employees (B-Y), 1934-1966 (Box 27, Folder 234)
    - Alphabetical - Employees (B-Y), 1934-1966 (Box 27, Folder 235)
      Resticted material
    - Alphabetical - Evans, Fannie, 1922-1930 (Box 27, Folder 236)
    - Alphabetical - "Famous People", 1946-1966 (Box 27, Folder 237)
    - Alphabetical - Fosdick, Raymond B., 1919-1932, 1958, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 238)
    - Alphabetical - Gibbs, Macqueen, c. 1932 (Box 28, Folder 239)
    - Alphabetical - Hooker, Blanche Ferry, 1932, 1955-1956 (Box 28, Folder 240)
    - Alphabetical - Hooker, Elon H., 1933-1937 (Box 28, Folder 241)
    - Alphabetical - Huntley, William Moscoe, 1944-1955, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 242)
    - Alphabetical - Jaffray, Edith H., 1927-1929 (Box 28, Folder 243)
    - Alphabetical - Johnson, James Weldon, 1930 (Box 28, Folder 244)
    - Alphabetical - Kelly, Anna, 1926-1929 (Box 28, Folder 245)
    - Alphabetical - Kline, Lillian, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 246)
    - Alphabetical - Lagerburg, George, 1922-1927 (Box 28, Folder 247)
    - Alphabetical - Looseley, Alice, 1924-1926, 1932 (Box 28, Folder 248)
    - Alphabetical - Love, Sally, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 249)
    - Alphabetical - McEwen, Kay and Mac, 1930, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 250)
    - Alphabetical - Mauzé, Abby Rockefeller, 1912-1932 (Box 28, Folder 251)
    - Alphabetical - Milliken, Alida, 1927-1930, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 252)
    - Alphabetical - Milton, David, 1934-1949 (Box 28, Folder 253)
    - Alphabetical - Morris, Noel, 1924-1928 (Box 28, Folder 254)
    - Alphabetical - Murray, Hildegarde, 1959-1960, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 255)
    - Alphabetical - Ober, Frank, 1934 (Box 28, Folder 256)
    - Alphabetical - Olmsted, Frank Lincoln, 1920-1927 (Box 28, Folder 257)
    - Alphabetical - O'Malley, Helen Hooker, 1940, 1945, 1950-1956 (Box 28, Folder 258)
    - Alphabetical - Orton, Bella, 1920-1927 (Box 29, Folder 259)
    - Alphabetical - Osborn, A. Perry, 1949-1950 (Box 29, Folder 260)
    - Alphabetical - Pervy, Adolphe, 1929-1950 (Box 29, Folder 261)
    - Alphabetical - Peterson, Elizabeth ("Pete"), 1928-1931, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 262)
    - Alphabetical - Prentice, Alta Rockefeller, 1937, 1961, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 263)
    - Alphabetical - Prentice, Joan, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 264)
    - Alphabetical - Prentice, John Rockefeller, 1942 (Box 29, Folder 265)
    - Alphabetical - Prentice, Madeline, 1924-1931 (Box 29, Folder 266)
    - Alphabetical - Robb, Catharine, 1922-1930 (Box 29, Folder 267)
      - Robb, Catharine (Box P 170, Folder 4)
    - Alphabetical - Robb, Catharine, 1922-1930 (Box 29, Folder 268)
    - Alphabetical - Robb, Catharine, 1922-1930 (Box 29, Folder 269)
    - Alphabetical - Robertson, Douglas Martin, 1925-1931, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 270)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 271)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 272)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1913-1920 (Box 29, Folder 273)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1913-1920 (Box 29, Folder 274)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1921-1948 (Box 30, Folder 275)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1921-1948 (Box 30, Folder 276)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1921-1948 (Box 30, Folder 277)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1921-1948 (Box 30, Folder 278)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1921-1948 (Box 30, Folder 279)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1921-1948 (Box 30, Folder 280)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Almira, 1924-1925 (Box 30, Folder 281)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Blanchette Ferry, 1932, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 282)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, David, 1921-1929, 1932 (Box 30, Folder 283)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Faith, 1927-1933 (Box 30, Folder 284)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Isabel, 1928 (Box 30, Folder 285)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Sr., 1906-1908, 1913-1937 (Box 30, Folder 286)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1914-1948 (Box 31, Folder 287)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1914-1948 (Box 31, Folder 288)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1914-1948 (Box 31, Folder 289)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1914-1948 (Box 31, Folder 290)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1914-1948 (Box 31, Folder 291)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1914-1948 (Box 31, Folder 292)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1914-1948 (Box 31, Folder 293)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1914-1948 (Box 31, Folder 294)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1949-1960 (Box 32, Folder 295)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1949-1960 (Box 32, Folder 296)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1949-1960 (Box 32, Folder 297)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1949-1960 (Box 32, Folder 298)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr., 1949-1960 (Box 32, Folder 299)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, John D., Jr. - Philanthropic Commitments, 1931-1941 (Box 32, Folder 300)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Laurance S., 1921-1930 (Box 32, Folder 301)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1920-1931 (Box 32, Folder 302)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1920-1931 (Box 32, Folder 303)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, William, 1923-1931, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 304)
    - Alphabetical - Rockefeller, Winthrop, 1931-1961 (Box 33, Folder 305)
    - Alphabetical - Rowntree, Benjamin and David, 1940-1944 (Box 33, Folder 306)
    - Alphabetical - Rowntree, Peter, 1940-1952 (Box 33, Folder 307)
    - Alphabetical - Russell, Bob, 1923-1930 (Box 33, Folder 308)
    - Alphabetical - Scales, Florence, 1914, 1920-1927, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 309)
    - Alphabetical - Sheppard, Merrill, 1945-1955 (Box 33, Folder 310)
    - Alphabetical - Southam, Margaret, 1930, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 311)
    - Alphabetical - Sterling, Duncan, 1922-1925, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 312)
    - Alphabetical - Stewart, Katharine S., 1930, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 313)
    - Alphabetical - Sweetser, Adelaide, 1934-1958, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 314)
    - Alphabetical - Sweetser, Arthur, 1928-1941, 1949, 1959 (Box 34, Folder 315)
      - Sweetser, Arthur (Box P 170, Folder 5)
    - Alphabetical - Sweetser, Arthur, 1928-1941, 1949, 1959 (Box 34, Folder 316)
    - Alphabetical - Sweetser, Ruth, 1928, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 317)
    - Alphabetical - Stewart, Latimer, 1926, 1929-1932, 1946 (Box 34, Folder 318)
    - Alphabetical - Stewart, Sissy, 1929, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 319)
    - Alphabetical - Stickney, Betty, 1927-1932, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 320)
    - Alphabetical - Swope, David, 1924-1930 (Box 34, Folder 321)
    - Alphabetical - Thompson, Benjamin A., 1924-1926 (Box 34, Folder 322)
    - Alphabetical - Villard, Dorothea, 1930, n.d. (Box 34, Folder 323)
    - Alphabetical - Wakefield, Anna M., 1922-1929 (Box 34, Folder 324)
    - Alphabetical - Wald, Lillian D., 1930 (Box 34, Folder 325)
    - Alphabetical - Worthley, Wallace F., 1918, 1921-1924 (Box 34, Folder 326)
  - Asian Interests, 1949-1969 1949-1961; 3
    Arranged alphabetically by geographical area, country, or organizational name.
    Through correspondence, reports, and memoranda, this subseries documents Rockefeller's interest in and commitment to Asia. Rockefeller was deeply concerned about the need for increasing America's understanding and appreciation of the peoples of Asia. To that end, he was involved in the support of cultural exchange programs; the revival of the Japan Society; the formation of the Asia Society; the construction of Asia House, the Asia Society's New York City headquarters; and the construction of the International House of Japan in Tokyo. The files documenting the teaching of the English language in Japan (folders 452-455) reflect Rockefeller's belief in the importance of English to Japan's growth in the international community. Also included here are files relating to the Council on Economic and Cultural Affairs, Inc. (CECA), an organization established by Rockefeller in 1953 to stimulate and support economic and related activities focusing on Asia. Rockefeller's work for the John Foster Dulles peace mission to Japan in 1951 led to a renewed acquaintance with Shigeharu Matsumoto, with whom he had worked at the Institute of Pacific Relations conference in 1929. The Matsumoto and Rockefeller families became close friends. Included in this subseries are Rockefeller's report for Dulles and the State Department (folder 446), as well as correspondence between Matsumoto and JDR 3rd (folders 477-478). Also represented here are two commercial ventures developed by Rockefeller to sell in the United States quality merchandise manufactured in Asia, namely, Products of Asia, Inc. and Products of India, Inc. These companies, which were meant to increase trade and encourage cultural contact, were sold in 1965.
    For additional Matsumoto family correspondence see series 3, subseries 2, folder 147.
    - Asia - General, 1949-1953 (Box 35, Folder 327)
    - Asia - General, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 328)
    - Asia - General, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 329)
    - Asia - General, 1955 (Box 35, Folder 330)
    - Asia - General, 1956 (Box 35, Folder 331)
    - Asia - General, 1957 (Box 35, Folder 332)
    - Asia - General, 1958 (Box 35, Folder 333)
    - Asia - General, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 334)
    - Asia - General, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 335)
    - Asia - General, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 336)
    - Asia - General, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 337)
    - Asia - General, 1961 (Box 36, Folder 338)
    - Asia Society - General, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 339)
    - Asia Society - General, 1956 (Box 36, Folder 340)
    - Asia Society - General, 1957 (Box 36, Folder 341)
    - Asia Society - General, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 342)
    - Asia Society - General, 1957-1958 (Box 37, Folder 343)
    - Asia Society - General, 1957-1958 (Box 37, Folder 344)
    - Asia Society - General, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 345)
    - Asia Society - General, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 346)
    - Asia Society - General, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 347)
    - Asia Society - General, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 348)
    - Asia Society - General, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 349)
    - Asia Society - Applications for Positions (CLOSED FOLDER), 1956-1957, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 350)
    - Asia Society - Asia House - General, 1956-1961 (Box 38, Folder 351)
    - Asia Society - Asia House - Construction, 1958-1960 (Box 38, Folder 352)
    - Asia Society - Asia House - Gallery, 1957-1961 (Box 38, Folder 353)
    - Asia Society - Asia House - Gallery Committee Meetings, 1959-1961 (Box 38, Folder 354)
    - Asia Society - Asia House - Gallery Opening, 1959-1960 (Box 38, Folder 355)
    - Asia Society - Asia House - Goldstone, Harmon H., 1956-1958 (Box 38, Folder 356)
    - Asia Society - Asia House - Guyer Lawsuit, 1959-1961 (Box 38, Folder 357)